MATTHEW ABERHAM

Boca Raton, FL

t: (631) 742-3213 e: matthew.aberham@gmail.com

Proactive, humble, full-stack engineer with a focus on the UI-stack. My expertise is in modern web technologies such as Vue, React, and LESS/SASS. I consider myself framework-agnostic and feel comfortable using whichever tool is appropriate for the use-case. I never stop learning and thrive in challenging, encouraging, diverse environments.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Perficient, Inc. -- Remote

Solutions Architect, Manager (UI/Full-stack)

August 2021 - Present

Technologies: React (Next), Vue (Nuxt), CSS (Sass), GraphQL, Webpack, Jest, .NET, Sitecore, Azure, Git

- Architecting large-scale React/Vue apps using Next/Nuxt built on Sitecore CMS, .NET MVC, and a collection of microservices
- Creating Design Systems of reusable components that surge development throughput, reduce code redundancy, and increase maintainability; all supported by Storybook documentation and full-coverage unit tests
- Auditing site performance and identifying opportunities to increase page load speeds, Lighthouse scores, and an optimized Critical Rendering Path leading to higher rankings on Google and thereby reduced marketing costs
- Managing a team of internal developers while serving as the designated lead on the client's development team
- Actively contributing to the hiring process by conducting interviews and defining role requirements

Lead Technical Consultant (UI/Full-stack Engineer)

March 2019 – August 2021

- Leading the front-end team during the development of the Publix.com website rebuild; receiving the highest level of ADA accessibility amongst food retail websites (per Miami Lighthouse for the Blind)
- Defining code patterns through example, code reviews, and code linting

Senior Technical Consultant (UI Developer)

February 2018 – March 2019

- Collaborating in a large, multi-team environment to build customized e-commerce, marketing, and customer experiences
- Implementing a system for builds and continuous integration using Webpack, Gulp, and Azure Pipelines

Threshold 360, LLC -- Remote

Full-stack Software Engineer

October 2016 - February 2018

Technologies: JavaScript/React, Mocha/Chai, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, AWS (S3, Lambda), Heroku, Git

- Developing an interactive virtual tour application built on React that enables users to navigate inside the captured locations
- Surging marketing engagement by developing an app that mirrors a potential client's site with the tour app embedded
- Constructing responsive dashboards and interfaces using React, Redux, and Ruby
- Developing a React application for manually redacting faces in images, supplemented by automated processes
- Building RESTful APIs to support single-page applications as well as for use by licensees to securely access proprietary data

Home Shopping Network, Inc. -- St. Petersburg, FL

Software Engineer I

May 2014 - October 2016

Technologies: JavaScript, C# .NET, ASP, Java, MSSQL, Oracle DB, IIS, TFS

- Digitizing call center workforce planning by developing a web application for agents to schedule shifts and manage time-off
- Modernizing the Order Management System front-end after IE8 support ended, saving HSN from costly upgrades
- Integrating Oracle's Omnichannel marketing into Restful APIs to support HSN.com
- Redeveloping legacy web applications with .NET MVC and modern front-end JavaScript

VIP Software Co. -- St. Petersburg, FL

Web Developer Technologies Issue Soviet Handlaham in Bulbu on Brille AMC Handlaham

October 2013 - May 2014

Technologies: JavaScript, Handlebars.js, Ruby on Rails, AWS, Heroku, Git

- Supporting data aggregation by scripting Node-based web scrapers
- Assisting development of a Websocket-based messaging application plugin
- Performing content updates and SEO enhancements on client websites

EDUCATION

The University of Tampa -- Tampa, FL

May 2014

Bachelor of Science in Management Information Systems (MIS)

CERTIFICATIONS / OTHER

Sitecore Platform Associate Developer, Level 2 Award in Wines (WSET), French Language (B2)